sldn.org 2010-06-24

# Servicemembers Legal Defense Network

Servicemembers Legal Defense Network makes every attempt to protect the privacy of our web visitors. 

Servicemembers Legal Defense Network ("SLDN" or "we", "us", "our") shares your concern about the protection of your personal information online. This is our policy regarding the privacy of personal information we collect on the SLDN.org website (the "Site"). Please note that this Privacy Policy does not govern our collection and use of information off-line. 

We do not knowingly collect personal information from anyone under 13 years old. If you are under 13 years old, please do not provide us with any such information. 

## Information that We Collect and Track

As further described below, we collect two types of information about Site visitors: (i) personal information that individual visitors provide when contributing to SLDN, or voluntarily at certain other points; and (ii) tracking data, which is automatically collected from every Site visitor. 

## Personal Information

We collect personal information about you, such as your name, e-mail address, postal address, phone number and credit card information, when you volunteer such information, for example when you complete our contribution form (the "Personal Information"). Wherever we collect Personal Information from you on the Site, we will make an effort to include a link to this Privacy Policy on that page. 

## E-Mails to SLDN

If you e-mail us, we may keep a record of your correspondence, and you may receive one or more reply e-mails from us emanating from the SLDN.org domain. Please be aware that many e-mail applications retain a copy of all sent messages in a "Sent Items", "Outbox" or similar folder, thus it may be possible for others with access to such folders to view any e-mails you send us. 

## Action Alerts

You may subscribe to our Action Alert listserv by providing your e-mail address and, at your option, your first and last name, at the Action Alert subscription page. If you join the Action Alert listserv, you will automatically receive various e-mail updates and bulletins that we send out on a periodic basis containing selected articles and other information. You may unsubscribe to the Action Alert listserv at any time by visiting the Action Alert subscription page. 

## Petitions

We may provide visitors with online petitions from time to time. Although such petitions, by their nature, involve our disclosure of Personal Information to third parties, participation in such petitions is voluntary. We may also use information obtained through online petitions for internal marketing purposes. 

## Contributions

We collect Personal Information from you when you contribute to SLDN, including credit card information. Unless you elect otherwise when you submit such information, we may (i) include your name on donor and supporter lists, and (ii) share your Personal Information with like-minded organizations, who may contact you regarding their services. Like most organizations, we also hire companies to provide certain administrative services that require access to member information, such as processing address labels, managing databases, and sending mailing. We may also combine the information you provide with other personal information obtained by us. In addition, we may use your Personal Information to send you information about SLDN and our activities, unless you contact us and request that we not send you such information. 

## Events

We collect Personal Information from you when you request information about our events or sponsorship opportunities, and when you buy tickets through the Site. Unless you elect otherwise when you submit such information, we may  
(i) include your name on donor and supporter lists (if applicable), and  
(ii) share your Personal Information with like-minded organizations, who may contact you regarding their services.  
In addition, we may use such Personal Information to send you materials regarding SLDN and our activities, unless you contact us and request that we not send you such information. 

## Tracking Data

Tracking data consists of information we collect automatically from each Site visitor that is not associated with an identifiable individual. Such tracking data includes information such as the Site visitor's browser type, operating system, Internet service provider or referring site. Tracking data also includes aggregate information, such as the total number of Site or page visits, and the average time visitors spend on the Site. 

## How We Use the Information

We use and disclose information obtained from Site visitors as stated in this Privacy Policy and as permitted by law. 

We will not disclose any Personal Information to third parties, except when we believe in good faith that the law requires it; to protect the rights, property, security or safety of SLDN, Site visitors or the public; to respond to an emergency; as authorized by the submitting party; or as otherwise stated in this Privacy Policy. We use tracking data to create aggregate reports on visitor demographics and Site traffic patterns, which we use for a variety of purposes, for example, to improve the Site or to seek funding. 

Unless you opt-out as provided herein, SLDN may:  
(i) send you, by postal mail or e-mail, solicitations to support SLDN or similar organizations or causes;  
(ii) identify you as a donor and/or supporter of SLDN;  
and (iii) disclose your Personal Information to like-minded organizations for purposes of contacting you regarding such organizations. 

## Service Providers

We work with third parties who provide services including but not limited to website hosting, data collection and hosting, order processing and fulfillment, credit card clearance, e-commerce affiliation, e-mailing and other services of an administrative nature. Personal Information, including financial information, may be shared with such third parties for the purpose of providing such services. 

## Cookies

We do not currently use cookies (that is, small data files containing information such as a Site visitor's browser session ID that are written to the Site visitor's hard drive by a web server) or other similar tracking technologies to collect information from Site visitors. But please note that evidence of your visit to the Site may nevertheless be retained on your computer, for example, in your browser's "History", "Temporary Internet Files" or similar files. 

## Opting-Out

You may opt-out of receiving solicitations from us, or from having us disclose your Personal Information to like-minded organizations for purposes of contacting you regarding such organizations. You may do this as described above by removing the check(s) from the appropriate check box(es) on the applicable online form. You may also do this at any time by sending a request by e-mail to [sldn@sldn.org](mailto:sldn@sldn.org) or by letter to the address provided under "Contact Information" below. 

From time to time, we may e-mail Site visitors important information regarding their use of the Site or changes to this Privacy Policy. Site visitors may not opt out of receiving such information.  
Correcting or Deleting Your Information. 

You may correct or request the deletion of your Personal Information by sending your request by e-mail, together with your name to [sldn@sldn.org](mailto:sldn@sldn.org). If you request that we correct or delete such information in our databases, we will endeavor to comply with your request as soon as reasonably practicable. Please note that we may need to retain certain information about you for record keeping purposes, and there may also be residual information about you that will remain within our databases and other records. 

We reserve the right to contact former Site users from time to time. 

## Revisions to Policy

Please note that, by using the Site, you signify your agreement to this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Site. We reserve the right to revise this Privacy Policy from time to time. 

Your continued use of the Site subsequent to changes to this Privacy Policy will mean that you accept such changes. To determine whether this Privacy Policy has been changed since your last visit to the Site, please refer to the "Last Updated" information at the top of this page. 

## Leaving the Site

Please note that third parties may collect information about you, through cookies or other technologies, when you link to their websites through our Site. You acknowledge that we do not monitor or control the information collection or privacy practices of these or any other third parties, and are not responsible for their practices or the content of their websites. You should review the privacy policies of such third parties to understand how they collect and use information. 

## Assignment

We reserve the right to transfer any and all information that we collect from Site visitors to a third party in the event that we sell or transfer all or a significant portion of our assets related to the Site to such third party. 

## Security

We use reasonable security methods to protect the data that resides on our servers. But because no security system is impenetrable, we cannot guarantee the security of our servers. It is also possible that information you seek to supply to us will be intercepted during transmission. 

## Contact Information

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or the Site, please send an e-mail to [[sldn@sldn.org](mailto:sldn@sldn.org)](mailto:sldn@sldn.org) or a letter to "Privacy Policy Inquiries" at the following address: 

SLDN  
P.O. Box 65301  
Washington, D.C. 20035-5301 

_The Site and this Privacy Policy, © 2008 Servicemembers Legal Defense Network. All rights reserved._
